Kashiful Haque

 $+918240868544 \mid \underline{haque.kashiful7@gmail.com} \mid \underline{github/kashifulhaque} \mid \underline{linkedin/kashifulhaque} \mid \underline{ifkash.vercel.app}$

Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in Backend Development, Data Science, AI, ML and NLP. Expertise in fine-tuning LLMs, Generative AI and building RAG solutions. Studied Data Science at IIT Madras.

Work Experience

Associate Software Engineer

07/2023 – Present

Electronics for Imaging

Bangalore, India

- Built an audio fingerprinting solution to identify ads played on commercial stations like TV, etc.
- Developed vector database solution for superior image and text search experience.
- Built RAG based FieryGPT using LLaMa 3.1 8B LLM, trained on company data for Question and Answering.

Data Scientist, Intern

01/2023 - 07/2023

Electronics for Imaging

Bangalore, India

- Improved efficiency by developing a pipeline to eliminate manual labour in text extraction.
- Created realistic conversational dataset to amplify accuracy of text classification model.
- Built cost-effective solution for creating product mockups using ImageMagick & Node.js/Python, surpassing results of expensive Photoshop APIs hence saving significant costs for the company.

Fullstack Developer, Intern

07/2022 - 12/2022

Corteva Agriscience

Hyderabad, India

- Improved Flask codebase, resulting in 15% faster AutoML job triggering on Kubernetes.
- Led migration of refactoring of Flask monolith to scalable APIs, improving scalability and reduced deployment time by around 10%

Education

Indian Institute of Technology Madras

12/2020 - 09/2024

Bachelor of Science, Data Science and Applications

University of Calcutta

08/2016 - 03/2019

Bachelor of Technology, Electronics and Communications Engineering

Projects and Blogs

Odeer • git repo

Go, Gin, Cloudflare

Beginner's Guide to CUDA Programming • blog here

C++, CUDA, Google Colab

berzifetch • git repo

Rust, system fetch, Linux

Vuether • git repo • website

Vue, REST API, OpenWeatherMap

Skills

- Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, C++, Rust, SQL
- Node.js, Express.js, Vue, Angular, FastAPI, Flask, Tailwind
- NumPy, Pandas, scikit-learn, Pytorch, huggingface, JAX, NLTK, spaCy, CUDA
- Vector database, Qdrant, MySQL, SQLite, Redis, Docker, Git, Linux